This looks very old.
What is it?
Dunno.
Apparently, we confiscated it
as part of some case a long time ago.
I see...
So, what do you want me to do with it?
If you head west and cross the ocean,
there's a place called Qunorts,
the Town of Freedom.
This job is to deliver this box
to the United Magic Association
branch office there.
I see.
You just have to deliver it and get paid.
Easy, right?
What, that's it?
Why don't you want to do
such an easy job yourself, Teach?
Because I'm going on vacation.
Vacation?
I've been working too much. I'm tired.
I see...
Just make sure you don't open the box.
Something dangerous might be inside.
Aye-aye, sir!
I will make sure not to open it!
Well, I'm off, then!
Well then, I guess I should go, too.
"The Two Teachers"
You're working at a stuffy place, as usual.
It's been a year already, huh?
Time and tide wait for no one.
Time flies, doesn't it?
You an old lady or something?
Well? Are you ready?
Probably not, right?
Please wait one moment.
I'll be ready soon.
Miss Fran, do you have
urgent business somewhere?
No, I'm going on vacation.
Vacation?
Goodbye.
Kids, make sure you practice your magic.
What? You took on an apprentice?
Her name's Saya.
Apparently, she knows your apprentice.
Saya...
Oh, the girl Elaina helped
become an apprentice witch.
It's a small world, isn't it?
Definitely.
I met Elaina, too.
Oh, my.
When I told Saya, she was
so frustrated, she wanted to die.
At any rate, it's strange, isn't it?
Huh?
I never thought you and I would end up
vacationing together every year like this.
Right? I didn't like you at first, Fran.
And I didn't like you, Sheila.
This is the story
of when I was still an apprentice
witch traveling with my teacher.
Huh? What did you just say, ma'am?
I think I'm going to take on an apprentice.
Um, am I not an apprentice?
I was thinking I'd like another one.
I think that should be your decision.
But if I decide without asking you,
you'll get mad, right?
You already have someone in mind
for your other apprentice, don't you?
Bingo.
I knew it.
Don't worry, Fran.
What?
She's a good girl,
so I'm sure you'll like her, too.
Hey, over here!
You're late, Teach!
You've got guts to make me wait.
Sorry about that.
It took some time to convince my apprentice.
Will you please refrain
from telling lies so casually?
Oh?
So she's my senior apprentice?
She looks really weak.
Huh? Whaddaya want?
Don't stare at me. You wanna fight?
Ma'am, just what part of her is a "good girl"?
She's been glaring at me and spewing
insults since the moment we met.
What'd you say?!
Now, now, you're fellow apprentices,
so you need to get along.
Very well.
Nice to meet you. What's your name?
I have no name I want to give you!
This is Fran. And this is Sheila.
Be nice to each other from now on.
Ma'am, I don't think that's possible.
And so, my teacher and I began
our journey together with Sheila.
The two of us were like oil and vinegar.
What shall we have for dinner?
Fish? Or Beef?
I'd like fish.
I want meat.
Huh? You wanna fight?
Is that all you know how to say?
Are you stupid? Are you an idiot?
Is that all you can say?
You've got a puny vocabulary.
Then, let's meet in the middle and have bread.
Huh?
Fire magic and ice magic.
Which shall I teach you today?
I'd like to learn about ice magic.
Huh? It should be fire. Stop messing around!
Then, let's meet in the middle
and take a break today.
If your wand gets taken away,
how would you fight?
With martial arts! Teach us some martial arts!
Please teach us how to use a bow.
Huh?!
Then, let's meet in the middle.
I'll teach you how to use knives.
Knives?!
This is how you hide them.
When you draw them, do it...
...like this,
in a sexy way.
You're the only person I don't think
I could ever become friends with.
Oh, my, what a coincidence.
You're the only person I don't think I
could ever become friends with.
During our travels over many months,
we took on a job from United Magic Association
in Qunorts, the Town of Freedom.
"No mages!"
"Don't fear mages!"
"Mages are children of the devil."
What the heck? Are they picking a fight with us?
It appears magic users like us
are not welcome in this country.
I wonder.
Just because something like this exists here
doesn't mean we should
reject the entire country.
If we do, then we'd be the same as those
putting up these posters and signs.
Welcome! We have been waiting for you!
Madam Witch, to cut to the chase, the job is--
How much does it pay?
I was going to tell you
what the job was first...
How much?
Um... ten gold coins.
Oh, she looks really happy.
And? What's the job?
Right, working behind the scenes in this town
is a suspicious group calling
themselves the Curio Company.
I see. The Curio Company.
I'm sure you've seen the posters and
signs around town defaming mages...
Oh!
Those, huh?
The Curio Company is a band of robbers
made up of people who can't use magic.
Since they can't use magic,
they can't stand the mages
who can get in their way,
so they harass and defame mages.
Why don't you guys just catch them?
You're mages, right?
It should be a piece of cake.
Is it really necessary to pay
a large sum to travelers
to resolve the situation?
You're absolutely right, but...
You have other reasons, right?
Yes.
The Curio Company has some mysterious tools.
Mysterious tools?
A sword that can cut
an unlimited number of times,
guns that can shoot hundreds of bullets,
matches that show visions of mythical beasts...
They're mysterious objects that
can draw out the user's special powers
to make them as strong as,
or even stronger than mages.
Tools like that exist?
Yes. They are able to use
tools like that skillfully,
leading mages around by the nose
and then escaping successfully every time.
In this town, no one trusts that
mages can do anything anymore.
Very well. I promise that
this will be taken care of.
Thank you very much!
If such a refined witch as yourself
gets involved, then those guys--
Oh, no.
Not by me.
By these two. Right?
Huh?!
Catch those Curio Company guys together.
Even if they have some annoying tools,
that shouldn't be a problem
for my apprentices, right?
If you mess up,
you'll be expelled.
Expelled...
I think we were both thinking
the same thing back then.
"I'll catch the Curio Company
myself and get her expelled."
W-Wait! Please, wait!
Sorry! It was my fault! Just spare my life--
I won't take your life.
All I want is that tool you have.
The sword?
Fine. You can have this sword!
And, I also have some questions--
Hey, wait a minute.
I saw him first.
He's my prey.
I'm the one who cornered this man.
No, I used you to corner him.
In other words, I'm ranked
higher than you. Get it?
No, and even if I did,
I wouldn't hand him over to you.
--Huh?!
What are you doing?
Are you trying to get in my way?
Or do you want our teacher to recognize you?
Shut up. It has nothing to do with you!
In this way, we just kept sabotaging each other…
--In the end, days passed,
--Thanks for waiting.
--and we were unable to catch
anyone from the Curio Company.
--Thanks.
--and we were unable to catch
anyone from the Curio Company.
You're the witch called Fran, right?
Where did you learn my name?
Don't worry about the details.
More importantly, is your work going well?
Does it look like it is?
Hm… "Curio Company leader declares
beheading of mages attacking comrades."
Looks like we're living in violent times.
No, this is exactly what I wanted.
Why? They want to kill you.
Which means they'll come find me, right?
It saves me the trouble of finding them.
Oh? You seem very confident.
Yes. I mean, you actually have come.
Are you the leader of the Curio Company?
Oops, don't think you're
going to resist or anything.
If you make any weird moves,
I'll cut off your head right here,
just like the newspaper headline said.
Take her away. We're going to dispose of her!
Yes'm!
What the heck? Don't get caught so easily.
You're a useless senior apprentice.
So you were caught, as well?
You are a completely useless junior apprentice.
You mages are always like this.
Getting in the way of our work all the time!
Thanks to you, we keep failing at our jobs!
I can't take it. I really can't take it.
And you lot!
To be bested by a couple of
little apprentice witches like this...
We finally got people
to lose confidence in mages,
and now you've let people trust in them again.
Are you trying to make all our work go to waste?
How can you call yourselves part
of the Curio Company like that?
Get your heads back in the game!
Yes'm!
We could hear everything you were
talking about earlier, you know?
What, is getting in our way
like playtime for you?
Just beating the crap out of you guys
can't even be called playtime.
Y-You little--
Boss!
Dispose of them now! Immediately!
Yes'm!
Take that!
B-Boss!
You little--
Wh-What are you doing?!
Hurry up and kill them!
Yes'm!
Could it be that you got yourself
caught on purpose, too?
I thought I'd sneak in and
round them all up at once.
It's reckless.
The same goes for you!
As expected of you honorable mages.
We're still unable to--
Shall we rest a bit before
we contact the association?
Yeah, let's.
Why do you want to study magic from our teacher?
The reason's not that interesting.
I learned magic on my own.
Huh? H-Hey! Wait!
I used that to get by,
but one day, the person
I tried to steal from was Teach.
She caught me easily.
That was the first time I heard about witches.
You didn't know about witches until then?
Well, no one told me.
But Teach told me.
She told me about how strong witches are,
and how much people respect them.
I thought that I could stop living
like a stray cat if I became a witch.
That's why I asked her
to make me her apprentice.
See? It's not that interesting, is it?
Well, what about you?
My reason's much less interesting.
There are no witches where I'm from.
So, if I become a witch,
then I'll be the only one in the country.
Then I'd always have a way
to make a living, right?
That's why.
So you're becoming a witch
for your own self-interest.
To summarize, yes.
What the heck? It's the same as me.
I suppose so.
Sheila and I rounded up all
the members of Curio Company.
Damn it! I'll get you back for this!
Won't they try something
again once they get out?
Maybe.
You two--you really did a good job.
After that, we continued
to travel with our teacher
and when she returned to her own country--
All right, finally!
Thank you very much!
They look good on you.
And now, you two are officially witches.
--Yes, ma'am!
--Yeah!
Also, for your witch titles--
Fran's hair is black, right?
So she'll be the Stardust Witch.
Huh?
And Sheila's hair is shiny, right?
So she'll be the Night Witch.
Huh?
Shouldn't I be the Night Witch,
since my hair is black?
And if my hair's shiny,
shouldn't I be the Stardust Witch?
The night...
...and stardust...
...set each other off so each looks its best.
I don't really understand.
Oh! Are you trying to say
that even though we're apart,
we'll still be together?
It looks like you were right.
But why did you base
our names on our hair color?
Because it's cool!
And so, our journey with our teacher ended.
I returned to my homeland and became a teacher,
and Sheila unexpectedly ended up
working for the United Magic Association.
You've really changed, haven't you?
Not really.
But anyway, I like our relationship now
better than when all we did was fight.
It's easier.
You really have changed.
We've just both grown up.
Come on, the sun's about to set.
Let's hurry.
Yes.
That small box...
That's--
Change of plan!
Wait, what's the matter?
Just follow me!
Jeez, you're inconsiderate, as usual.
Please wait!
That day, I was headed toward a certain town--
It was the town where, in volume four of
my favorite book, The Adventures of Niké,
the friendship of Niké's two apprentices,
Foula and Shiren, budded--
A sacred place for Niké fans.
That's right, it's Qunorts, the Town of Freedom.